（俄亥俄州 1995年）
嘿 小娜
Hey, Nat!
我们都倒过来了
We're both upside down.
我赌你会先撑不住
And I bet you're gonna fall down first.
才不 你先撑不住
No, you will.
你快撑不住了
You can't hold it much longer.
说了你会先撑不住的
Told you you'd fall down first.
我就说嘛 我就说嘛
I told you! I told you!
早告诉你了
Told you so!
妈妈
Mommy!
怎么回事
What happened?
她摔到膝盖了
She fell on her knee.
- 你磕到膝盖了吗 - 嗯
- Oh, you bump your knee? - Mmm-hmm.
哦…
Oh…
亲亲就不疼了 好了
Kiss it better. There we go.
别这样 小家伙
Oh, come on, little one.
站起来 没事了
Get up. You're okay.
走吧 你是个勇敢的姑娘
Come on. You're a brave girl.
你的痛苦只会让你变得更强
Your pain only makes you stronger.
- 你说对吧 - 没错
- Right, you? - Yeah.
- 对吧 - 你看
- Yeah? - Look!
森林的星星
Forest stars.
没错 你知道吗
Yeah. You know what?
它们其实是属于萤科的昆虫
Those are actually part of the Lampyridae family.
那种光 你看到它们发的光
And the glow, the glow that you see,
其实是因为一种化学反应
that comes from a chemical reaction called…
叫做生物发光
bioluminescence.
走吧 该吃晚饭了
Come on, time for dinner.
叫生物花光吗
Bio-goomin-feasants?
「生物花光」 没错
"Bio-goomin-feasants." That's right.
吃晚饭啦
Dinner!
来吃晚饭了 大姑娘
Come on, dinner, big girl!
我要奶酪焗意面
I want mac and cheese.
你要奶酪焗意面吗 好吧 那我就要…
Oh, you want mac and cheese? Okay. Well, I want…
鱼子酱和香槟
caviar and champagne.
去拿餐巾
Grab the napkins.
你端一下这个 谢谢
You take this. Thank you.
你能帮爸爸拿一下牧场沙拉酱吗
Oh, would you grab the ranch dressing for Dad?
好
Okay.
我最喜欢的蔬菜就是青豆
Green beans are my favorite vegetable.
爸爸回家了
Dad's home!
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Dad.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, baby.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
大家今天过得怎么样
How was everybody's day?
妈妈今天跟我说了小灯虫
Mommy taught me about lamp bugs.
- 小灯虫 - 我还跌倒磕伤了膝盖
- Lamp bugs. - And I fell and hurt my knee,
但是现在不疼了
but it doesn't hurt anymore.
- 嗯嗯 - 我们还在后院看到了萤火虫
- Mmm-hmm. - And we also saw fireflies in the backyard.
- 那是我今天最开心的时候 - 不
- That was my favorite part of the whole day. - No.
- 叶莲娜 我们每年都能看到萤火虫 - 我们有多少时间
- Yelena, we see fireflies every year. - How long do we have?
我也不知道 可能一个小时
I don't know. Like, an hour, maybe.
我不想走
I don't wanna go.
别这么说
Don't say that.
姑娘们…
Girls…
还记得我说过有一天我们要去大冒险吗
you remember when I told you that one day we would have that big adventure?
- 就在今天 - 好耶
- Today's the day. - Yay!
好 我们走
All right, let's go.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
- 快 我们得抓紧 - 谢谢
- Come on, we gotta hurry. - Thank you.
- 我还没穿鞋 - 谢谢 宝贝
- I don't have my shoes. - Thank you, baby.
没事 不用穿鞋
That's okay. You don't need your shoes.
- 但我还很饿 - 是吗 跟你说
- But I'm still hungry. - Yeah? Guess what?
我车里有水果卷
I got Fruit Roll-Ups in the car.
不 那个别带 放下 去车上等着
No, leave it, leave it, leave it. Go wait in the car.
- 东西在你那吗 - 在的
- You have it? - Yeah.
- 仅有这一份备份吗 - 只有这份没烧掉
- It's the only copy? - It's the only one not on fire.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
家
Home.
妈妈 你好笨
Mommy, you're silly.
我们才从家走
We just left home.
我想听我的歌
I want my song.
∮ 再见吧 美国派小姐 ∮
∮ Bye, bye, Miss American Pie ∮
∮ 开着雪佛兰上河堤 而河堤已干涸 ∮
∮ Drove my Chevy to the levee but the levee was dry ∮
∮ 老朋友们喝着黑麦威士忌 ∮
∮ Them good old boys were drinking whiskey and rye ∮
∮ 高声唱着「今日就是死期」 ∮
∮ Singing, "This'll be the day that I die" ∮
∮ 今日就是死期 ∮
∮ This'll be the day that I die ∮
∮ 你写过爱情之书吗 ∮
∮ Did you write the book of love ∮
∮ 你相信天国的上帝吗 ∮
∮ And do you have faith in God above ∮
∮ 如果这是圣经的指示 ∮
∮ If the Bible tells you so ∮
∮ 那你现在相信摇滚乐吗 ∮
∮ Now do you believe in rock and roll ∮
∮ 音乐可否拯救凡人的灵魂 ∮
∮ Can music save your mortal soul ∮
∮ 你可否教我跳上一曲 ∮
∮ And can you teach me how to dance real ∮
快走 叶莲娜 宝贝快走
Come on, Yelena. Hurry up, baby.
快走 快点 小娜 快 我们得走了
Let's go. Come on, Nat. Hurry up. We gotta go.
我们得走了 快 跑起来
We gotta go. Come on, you gotta run.
快点 亲爱的 宝贝
Come on. Honey, honey.
- 跟你妈妈走 跟着她 - 好
- Go with your mom. Go with your mom. - Okay.
- 小娜 快点 - 我来了
- Nat, hurry up! - I'm coming!
好了 系好安全带
Okay. Seat belts.
好吧 爸爸为什么不上飞机
Okay. Why isn't Dad in the plane?
他来了 他来了 宝贝 他很快就来
He's coming. He's coming, baby. He's coming.
妈
Mom?
Mom!
我需要你到前面来
I need you up here.
- 好的 - 好的
- Okay. - Okay.
朝右边打方向
I need you to pull right.
妈 你身上有血
Mom, you've got blood on you.
没事的 宝贝
It's okay, baby.
推那边的加速器
Hit the accelerator there.
开稳了 开稳了
Hold it steady, hold it steady.
速度达到55节你就拉升
You're gonna pull back at 55 knots.
我们一起来数
Let's count together.
45 50…
45, 50…
向后拉 你可以的
Pull back. You can do it!
用全力向后拉
Pull back. All your strength.
（古巴）
好了
Okay.
醒醒啊 妈妈
Get up, Mommy.
痛苦只会让你变得更强 记得吗？
Pain only makes you stronger, remember?
红色守卫者回来了
The Red Guardian returns.
红色守卫者凯旋而归
The Red Guardian returns triumphant.
拜托了 求求你别再给我安排潜伏任务了
Please, please, I beg you. No more undercover work.
我想要战斗 我想重新穿上战衣
I wanna get back in the action. I want my suit back.
我太想念那感觉了
I wanna get back in it.
德雷科夫将军 我已经这样过了三年多了
General Dreykov, it's been over three years.
妈妈对不起
Forgive me mom.
我好害怕
I'm scared.
永远别让他们动摇你的本心
Never let them take your heart.
一边去
Уйти в
东西拿到了吗？
Did you get it?
那北方研究所呢？
And the North Institute?
付之一炬了
Ashes.
一定会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
梅丽娜的情况怎么样？
How is Melina?
她会活下来的 她很顽强
She'll live. She's strong.
妈咪 妈妈
Mommy? Mom?
- 爸爸 - 我来处理
- Daddy! - I'll handle this.
- 爸爸 爸爸 - 叶莲娜
- Daddy! Daddy! - Yelena!
- 爸 - 离她远点
- Daddy! - Get away from her!
别碰她
Don't touch her!
我会开枪的
I will shoot.
不许碰她
Don't touch her!
我会把你们全都杀掉
I will kill you all!
我会开枪的
I will shoot.
你们不许碰她
Don't touch her.
宝贝
Honey.
你得把枪递给我
You're gonna need to hand me that gun.
我不想再回那地方去了
I don't wanna go back there.
我想留在俄亥俄州
I wanna stay in Ohio.
你们不能把她带走
You can't take her.
不能这样
You can't.
她才六岁
She's only six.
你被带走时候比她还小呢
You were even younger.
没事的
It's okay.
过来
Come here.
你们会没事的
You're gonna be all right.
知道为什么你们会没事吗
Do you know why it's gonna be all right?
因为我的女儿们 是世界上最坚强的女孩子
Cause my girls are the toughest girls in the world.
你们要照顾好彼此 好吗
You're gonna take care of each other, okay?
一切 一切都会好起来的
And everything, everything's gonna be fine.
那女孩 她身上憋着一股劲
That one, she has fire in her.
她叫什么
What was her name?
娜塔莎
Natasha.
啊…娜塔莎
Ah… Natasha.
《黑寡妇》
不要啊
No!
把残次品都清理掉
Remove all the defects.
那一个
That one.
还有她
and her.
不要
No!
叶莲娜
Yelena!
拿着 拿着它 不要
Take it! Take it! No!
不要啊
No!
从现在开始红房就是你的家了
The Red Room is your home now.
放开我 别碰我
Get off me! No!
有卧底间谍潜伏在我们的社区之中
Undercover spies in our communities.
他们用的是假身份 甚至伪装成一家人…
They took on false identities, even raised families…
（21年后）
- 他们上去了 长官 - 第一梯队视野清晰
- They're topside, sir! - Tier 1 has LOS!
我们已经封锁了所有出口
We've got all exits covered.
很好 保持警戒
All right. Stay alert.
正在派遣第一小队进入
I'm sending in alpha squad.
娜塔莎·罗曼诺夫违反了索科维亚协议
Natasha Romanoff is in violation of the Sokovia Accords.
她还袭击了瓦坎达的国王
She assaulted the king of Wakanda.
我们要拿她杀鸡儆猴
Make an example out of her.
- 喂 - 别这么做
- Yeah? - Don't do this.
- 别做什么 - 别追我了
- Do what? - Come after me.
我想说 你孤注一掷的样子是在自取其辱
I mean, you're embarrassing yourself. It looks desperate.
我以为你打给我是为了妥协
Thought maybe you'd be calling me to cut a deal.
因为从我的角度来看
'Cause from my vantage point,
孤注一掷的人 是你这个联邦逃犯
it's the federal fugitive who's desperate.
从我的角度来看 你需要卧床静养
From my vantage point, you look like you could use some bed rest.
你这是怎么了 心脏第二次搭桥了吧
What is this, your second triple bypass?
我才不必担心自己
I wouldn't worry about me.
我们抓到了巴顿 抓到了威尔逊 还有另一个家伙
We got Barton, we got Wilson and that other guy,
难以置信的会缩小的罪犯
the incredible shrinking convict.
罗杰斯还在逃 你现在可是孤立无援
Rogers is on the run. You got no friends.
你还能去哪
Where you gonna go?
罗斯 在遇到你之前 我已经有过多重身份
I've lived a lot of lives before I met you, Ross.
你就不该这么麻烦来一遭 我说完了
You shouldn't have gone to all this trouble. I'm done.
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff?
罗斯国务卿 这是出空城计
Got an empty nest, Secretary Ross.
这是她的追踪器 先生
Her tracker, sir.
（摩洛哥）
目标已瞄准 她在等包裹
Eyes on target. Waiting for the package.
我已经瞄准目标旁边的一个人
I have sights on collateral one.
数到三开火
Firing in place of three.
五 四…
Five, four…
她发现我们了 目标放置烟雾弹
She made us. Target deployed smoke.
她带着包裹跑了 你守住高地 我转地面行动
She's on foot with the package. Stay high. I'm going to ground.
奥克莎娜
Oksana.
噢 不
Oh, no.
我干了什么
What did I do?
解放其他人
Free the others.
叶莲娜 我们需要你的情况报告
Yelena, we need a status report.
叶莲娜 请报告你的状况
与你的队长会和
Converge on team leader.
德雷科夫将军 我们当中出现了叛徒
General Dreykov, we have a deserter.
请问是否需要激活模仿大师
Permission to activate Taskmaster Protocol?
笑一个
Smile.
（挪威）
在索科维亚协议事件之后 国家展开了对剩余复仇者的追捕…
After the Sokovia Accords, the hunt is on for the remaining Avengers…
史蒂夫·罗杰斯与娜塔莎·罗曼诺夫目前在逃
…Steve Rogers and Natasha Romanoff are currently on the run.
你睡了我的床
You're in my bed.
我…我连被子都没盖
I'm… I'm not even under the covers.
我要的你都准备好了吗
Did you get everything on my list?
准备好了护照 准入签证 几张当地司机的驾照
Got passports, entry visas, a couple of local driver's licenses.
混搭着用的话 你应该能转换20个左右的身份
Mix and match, you should be able to stretch it to 20 or so identities.
范尼·隆巴顿
Fanny Longbottom?
- 怎么了 - 还怎么了 你是12岁小孩吗
- What? - What, are you 12?
这个名字合法的
That is a legitimate name.
我们外面有台发电机
We've got a generator outside.
烧汽油的 那个化粪池过几个礼拜要冲冲了
It's petrol-powered. And the septic tank will need a flush in a couple of weeks,
但是我也找好了人来做
but, you know, I've got a guy coming for that.
扔垃圾得到城里 开车只要二十分钟
You have to haul your rubbish into town. It's just a 20-minute drive.
你要的基础五金件我都放到楼梯下面了
I've got your basic hardware kit stashed under the stairs.
很好
Nice.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我为什么不好
Why wouldn't I be?
我听说了 有关复仇者联盟的分崩离析…
I hear things. You know, something about the Avengers getting divorced…
啊 没事
Ugh. It's fine.
我一个人待着反而更好
I'm actually better on my own.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
确定
Yeah.
你知道的 你可以和我倾诉
Because you can tell me, you know.
朋友就是要这样嘛
That's the way the whole friends thing works.
我懂 我有朋友
I know. I have friends.
有朋友的人才不会来找我
People who have friends don't call me.
我不是花钱让你担心我的
And I don't pay you to worry.
噢 嘿
Oh, hey.
这些垃圾都是什么玩意
What's all this junk?
噢 就是些从布达佩斯安全屋寄来的邮件和私人物品
Oh, just some mail and personals from the Budapest safe house.
布达佩斯吗
Budapest?
是 布达佩斯
Yeah. Budapest.
- 不对 发音应该是「布达佩诗」 - 布达佩斯
- No, it's "Budapest." - Budapest.
布达佩斯
Budapest.
是「布达佩诗」
It's "Budapest."
无所谓了 我知道你不会再回到那了
Whatever. I knew you weren't going back there, so.
所以我把公寓租给别人了
I've got someone else in the flat now.
抱歉让你费这么大力气 我应该让你扔掉的
Sorry you went through the trouble. I would've told you to chuck it.
好吧 既然你不想要 那就扔进垃圾桶咯
Well, if you don't want it, throw it in the rubbish.
邦德先生 您又不是运动员
You're not a sportsman, Mr. Bond.
你为什么要破坏你跟我的宠物蟒蛇的会面呢
Why did you break up the encounter with my pet python?
因为我发现 他对我有意思
Because I discovered he had a crush on me.
- 登月一号准备发射… - 噢 真是时候
- Moonraker 1 on preset launch program… - Oh, great.
…两分钟后
…minus two minutes.
收回船员通道…
Retract crew access…
我很确定罗斯在这里没有司法权
I'm pretty sure Ross has no jurisdiction here.
你也应该知道我被惹怒的时候枪法更准
And you should know I'm a better shot when I'm pissed off.
你不是冲我来的
You're not here for me.
噢 糟糕
Oh, shit.
（布达佩斯）
我知道你在外面
I know you're out there.
我知道你知道我在外面
I know you know I'm out here.
那你为什么还偷偷摸摸地像探地雷一样
Then why are you skulking about like it's a minefield?
因为我不知道我能不能相信你
Cause I don't know if I can trust you.
有趣 我也准备问一样的问题
Funny, I was going to say the same thing.
那我们要像成年人一样谈谈吗
So, we gonna talk like grown-ups?
我们不就是成年人嘛
Is that what we are?
在我制服你之前 把枪放下
Put it down before I make you.
你把你的放下
You put yours down.
- 注意你的脚下 - 嗯
- Watch your step. - Huh.
躺下去 躺下
Stay down. Stay down.
别起来
Stay down.
住手
Stop.
停战
Truce.
你长大了
You've grown up.
废话
No shit.
你以前就来过布达佩斯 对吧
You had to come to Budapest, didn't you?
我来这是因为觉得你不会来
I came here because I thought you wouldn't.
不过既然你来了 我想问问什么子弹才能打成那样
But since you're here, what bullet does that?
不是子弹 是箭
Not bullets. Arrows.
啊 有道理
Ah, right.
如果你觉得我不会来这 为什么要给我寄去这些
If you didn't think I'd come here, why'd you send me this?
你又把它带回来了吗
You brought it back here?
我不是来和你交朋友的 不过你得告诉我那是什么
I'm not here trying to be your friend, but you need to tell me what that is.
是种合成气体
It's a synthetic gas.
反化学控制的中和剂
The counteragent to chemical subjugation.
气体可以使大脑的神经通路
The gas immunizes the brain's neuropathways.
免疫于外界操纵
from external manipulation.
或许你说点人能听懂的英语呗
Maybe in English next time?
它是思想控制的解药
It's an antidote to mind control.
你可真成熟
Real mature.
你怎么不把它拿给你的超级科学家朋友们看看呢
Why don't you take it to one of your super-scientist friends?
他们就能给你解释
They can explain it to you.
或许给托尼·斯塔克呗
Tony Stark, maybe?
哦 对 我们正冷战呢 所以…
Oh, yeah. We're not really talking right now, so…
真好 真会挑时间
Great. Perfect timing.
需要复仇者的时候怎么就找不到人了呢
Where's an Avenger when you need one?
我也不想待在这
I don't wanna be here.
我正逃亡呢 你可能会害死我
I'm on the run. You could've gotten me killed.
那你说我该怎么办
Well, what was I supposed to do?
你是我认识的唯一一个超级英雄
You're the only superhero person that I know.
正因如此我才寄给你的
That was the whole reason I sent it to you.
我一直在关注新闻
I kept checking the news,
期盼着看到美国队长摧毁红房
expecting to see Captain America bringing down the Red Room.
什么
What?
摧毁红房 你在说什么
Taking down the Red Room? What are you talking about?
它已经消失很多年了
It's been gone for years.
徳雷科夫已经死了
Dreykov's dead.
我亲手杀了他
I killed him.
你不会真的相信他死了吧 不会吧
You don't actually believe that, do you?
你真相信啊
You really do believe that.
徳雷科夫死了
Dreykov's dead.
我们几乎毁了整座城市才找到他
It took almost destroying the entire city just to get to him.
如果你那么确定 那你告诉我发生了什么
If you're so sure, then tell me what happened.
准确地告诉我
Tell me exactly.
我们布置了炸弹
We rigged bombs.
- 「我们」是谁 - 克林顿·巴顿
- Who's "we"? - Clint Barton.
杀死徳雷科夫是我叛逃进入神盾局的最后一步
Killing Dreykov was the final step in my defection to S.H.I.E.L.D.
就这么简单吗
Simple as that?
对 当然了 「简单」
Yeah, sure, "simple."
炸掉一个五层的大楼
That's what I'd call imploding a five-story building.
随后和匈牙利特种部队交火 我管这叫「简单」
and then shooting it out with the Hungarian Special Forces.
我们躲躲藏藏十天才从布达佩斯逃出来
Took 10 days in hiding before we could even get out of Budapest.
你检查过尸体了吗 确定杀死了吗
And you checked the body? Confirmed the kill?
已经没有能检查的尸体了
There was no body left to check.
你忘了徳雷科夫的女儿
You're forgetting Dreykov's daughter.
我们这是要往哪跑
Where are we trying to get?
找摩托车 在大楼东侧
Motorbike! East side of the building.
她们往东跑了 去房顶
They're going east, to the roof.
收到 马上追击
Copy, in pursuit.
我拉住你了
I got you!
不要
No!
嘿
Hey.
别动 你受伤了
Don't move. You're hurt.
让我帮帮你
Let me help you.
我不想这么做
I don't wanna do this.
- 你在做什么 - 是他逼我的
- What are you doing? - He's making me.
你现在相信我了吗
Do you believe me now?
还有多少人
How many others?
够多了
Enough.
- 哪个是你的 - 黑车 座椅是棕色的
- Which one's yours? - Black. Brown seat.
我钥匙呢
Where are my keys?
啊 贱人
…ah, bitch.
动作快点
Any day now.
你们没事吧
Are you okay?
妙啊
Fantastic.
你不能直接偷人家的车
You can't just steal a guy's car.
所以你想让我追着他把车还他吗
So you want me to chase him down and un-steal it?
- 行行好 别磨磨唧唧 - 闭嘴吧
- Okay. Any time now, please. - Shut up.
好吧 你有计划吗 还是我一直躲着就成了
Okay, you got a plan, or shall I just stay duck-and-cover?
我的计划是咱俩开车逃跑
Yeah, my plan was to drive us away.
那这计划烂透了
That's a shit plan.
不客气哦
You're welcome.
妈的 他追来了
Oh, shit. He's back.
系好安全带
Put your seat belt on.
你真是婆婆妈妈的
You're such a mom.
娜塔莎 不要
Natasha, no.
我觉得我在流血 我…
I think I'm bleeding. I'm…
不 现在不行 相信我
No. Not now, trust me.
你还好吗
You okay?
还好 计划不错
Yeah. Great plan.
我喜欢我差点流血至死的部分
I love the part where I almost bled to death.
这还挺舒服
This is cozy.
我和巴顿在这上面躲了两天
Barton and I spent two days hiding out up here.
那肯定很好玩
That must have been fun.
那家伙是谁啊
Who the hell is that guy?
徳雷科夫的特别项目
Dreykov's special project.
他可以模仿他见过的任何人
He can mimic anyone he's ever seen.
跟他打就像是对着镜子打架一样
It's like fighting a mirror.
德雷科夫只派他执行最高级别任务
Dreykov only deploys him for top-priority missions.
这完全不合理啊
This doesn't make any sense.
你忽视了重要细节 真相也就没法合理啊
Well, the truth rarely makes sense when you omit key details.
你这话是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
你只字未提德雷科夫女儿的事儿
You didn't say one word about Dreykov's daughter.
你杀了她
You killed her.
我也别无他法
I had to.
我得靠她才能找到德雷科夫
I needed her to lead me to Dreykov.
我们得确认德雷科夫在那栋楼里
We need confirmation Dreykov's in the building.
他停车了
His car is pulling up now.
德雷科夫的女儿是连带伤害
Dreykov's daughter was collateral damage.
我只有靠她来确认
I needed her to be sure.
娜塔莎 可以确认目标么
Natasha, we clear?
目标已确认
All clear.
结果现在你却在这里动摇
And here you are, not so sure.
我必须离开红房
I needed out.
红房还在运行 位置在哪
The Red Room's still active. Where is it?
我也一概不知
I have no idea.
德雷科夫时常变更基地位置
He moves location constantly.
出入口都有姑娘们把守 固若金汤
And every widow is sedated on entry and exit for maximum security.
我还是很难相信 他竟然能躲过我的视线
I'm just finding it hard to believe that he could stay off my radar.
嗨 想隐藏自己的人不会蠢到招惹复仇者的
Well, it's not smart to attack an Avenger if you want to stay hidden.
我意思是 你名声很大
I mean, the clue is in the name.
德雷科夫杀了你的话
Dreykov kills you,
那些大佬里就会有人来替你报仇
one of the big ones comes to avenge you.
等等 你说啥大佬
Wait, what are the big ones?
我觉得天神下凡打完架后应该不用嗑布洛芬
Well, I doubt the god from space has to take an ibuprofen after a fight.
你以为这些年来我在哪儿
Where did you think I was all this time?
我以为你逃了出去 过上了正常人的生活
I thought that you got out and were living a normal life.
那你就不曾联系我咯
And you just never made contact again?
讲真 我以为你不想见我
Honestly, I thought you didn't wanna see me.
我的天 扯犊子
God. Bullshit.
你只是不想要小妹妹拖你的后腿
You just didn't want your baby sister to tag along,
影响你和酷佬们拯救世界
whilst you saved the world with the cool kids.
你又不是我真正的妹妹
You weren't really my sister.
复仇者联盟也不是你真正的家人
And the Avengers aren't really your family.
- 你为什么老是那么做 - 做什么
- Why do you always do that thing? - Do what?
就你打架时候做的那个动作
The thing you do when you're fighting.
就…像这样…
The… Like, the…
你就是这么做的
This thing that you do.
一开打你就这样甩头发
when you whip your hair when you're fighting.
胳膊半张 头发后甩
with the arm and the hair.
就像是 摆了个战斗造型的感觉
And you do, like, a fighting pose.
就很…
It's a…
就是个战斗造型 简直装腔作势
It's a fighting pose. You're a total poser.
- 我才没有 - 哈哈
- I'm not a poser. - Haha.
得了吧你 其实造型很不错
Oh, come on. I mean, they're great poses,
但感觉你以为所有人都在看你似的
but it does look like you think everyone's looking at you, like,
每次都是
all the time.
你觉得我每次忙着摆造型
All that time that I spent posing,
其实都是想尽力做些善事
I was trying to actually do something good.
去弥补因为我们而造成的伤痛
to make up for all the pain and suffering that we caused.
不只是做一个训练有素的杀手
Trying to be more than just a trained killer.
哎 那你就是在自欺欺人了
Well, then you were fooling yourself.
伤痛不会就此休止 我们也仍旧是训练有素的杀手
because pain and suffering is every day and we are both still a trained killer.
不过我没有像你一样登上杂志封面罢了
Except I'm not the one that's on the cover of a magazine.
被小女孩们崇拜为英雄的杀手也不是我
I'm not the killer that little girls call their hero.
那种气体
That gas,
那个解毒剂
the counteragent,
是一位跟梅丽娜同期的年长「寡妇」秘密合成的
it was synthesized in secret by an older widow from Melina's generation.
我奉命执行回收它的任务 她对我使用了这种气体
I was on the mission to retrieve it, and she exposed me.
我却把解放了我的「寡妇」杀了
and I killed the widow that freed me.
你当时有得选么
Did you have a choice?
你只是经历过心理控制
What you experienced was psychological conditioning.
我说的可是被化学药品改变大脑机能
I'm talking about chemically altering brain functions.
本质上就大相径庭
They're two completely different things.
你的意识完全清醒 但不知道哪个你才是真实的
You're fully conscious, but you don't know which part is you.
我现在也不确定
I'm still not sure.
- 剩下的都在这儿了么 - 嗯哼
- Is that all there is left? - Mmm-hmm.
只有这个能阻止德雷科夫和他的「寡妇」网络了
It's the only thing that can stop Dreykov and his network of widows.
他还在夜以继日地纳新
He takes more every day.
招募无人保护的女孩们
Children who don't have anyone to protect them.
就像小时候的我们
Just like us when we were small.
大约二十人里能有一个经受住训练 蜕变为「寡妇」
Maybe one in 20 survives the training, becomes a widow.
其他人都死于他手
The rest, he kills.
对他而言 我们不过是物品
To him, we are just things.
是没身份的武器 可以随意丢弃
Weapons with no face that he can just throw away.
毕竟新人源源不绝
Because there is always more.
托你和阿列克谢的福 都没人试着找他
And no one's even looking for him, thanks to you and Alexei.
阿列克谢是谁
Alexei?
「咱爸」
"Dad."
你可曾找寻过父母 你的亲生父母
Did you ever look for your parents? Your real ones?
好吧 我亲妈把我遗弃在大街上 就像扔垃圾一样
Well, my mom abandoned me in the street like garbage.
你呢
What about you?
我的出生证明被销毁了 所以我自己另建了档案
They destroyed my birth certificate, so I reinvented it.
档案里我的父母还住在俄亥俄州
My parents still live in Ohio.
我姐去了大西部
My sister moved out west.
是嘛
Is that right?
设定上你是教科学的老师
You're a science teacher.
不过那只是兼职 尤其是你生了儿子之后
You're working part-time, though, especially after you had your son.
至于你丈夫 他负责房屋翻修
Your husband, he renovates houses.
我的故事可不是这样的
That is not my story.
那是啥样
What is your story?
我从不过长时间独处 所以无暇细想
I never let myself be alone long enough to think about it.
你可曾幻想过生育子女呢
Did you ever wish for kids?
我想养条狗
I want a dog.
你接下来要去哪
Where you gonna go?
不知道
I don't know.
我没有能回去的地方了
I don't really have anywhere to go back to,
所以去哪儿都行
so I guess anywhere.
- 你别 - 别什么
- Don't. - Don't what?
你这大英雄是要絮絮叨叨谆谆教导我了
You're going to give me some big hero speech,
我能觉察得到
I can feel it.
我其实不擅长说教
Speeches aren't really my thing.
哈
Huh.
这更像是一种邀请
It was more like an invitation.
去红房然后杀了德雷科夫吗
To go to the Red Room and kill Dreykov?
是的
Yeah.
尽管我们根本找不到红房在哪
Even though the Red Room is impossible to find.
尽管德雷科夫老奸巨猾难以下手
and Dreykov is too slippery to kill?
是
Yeah.
听起来工作量有点大
That sounds like a shitload of work.
是呢
Yup.
不过应该会很有趣
Could be fun, though.
是呢
Yup.
我看到他把钥匙放在哪了
I saw where he put the keys.
最上面的抽屉 绿色柜子
Top drawer, green cabinet.
你知道吗 这是我买给我自己的第一件衣服
You know, this is the first piece of clothing I've ever bought for myself.
就你身上那件
That?
- 嗯 你不喜欢吗 - 这难道不像…
- Yeah. You don't like it? - Is that like a…
军队剩余物资之类的吗
Is it army surplus, or…
好吧 这件衣服上有很多口袋
Okay, it has a lot of pockets.
但是我随时都用得上
But I use them all the time,
而且我自己还做了点改进
and I made some of my own modifications.
- 哦 是吗 - 随便你吧
- Oh, yeah? - Whatever.
别笑了 重点在于…
Shut up. The point is, I've never…
我以前没有掌控过我自己的人生 现在可以了
I've never had control over my own life before, and now I do.
我想做随我心意的事
I want to do things.
嗯…
Hmm…
我喜欢你的背心
I like your vest.
天呐 我就知道你喜欢 很酷 是吧
God. I knew it. I knew you did. It's so cool, right?
是很好看 我喜欢
It's good. Yes. I like it.
你都想不到你可以在口袋里面放多少东西
And you can put so much stuff in there. You wouldn't even know.
不过我真的不知道红房的具体位置 对不起
I really don't know where the Red Room is, though. I'm sorry.
没关系
I know.
但是我想有一个人肯定知道
But I think I know somebody who does.
哦是吗 谁啊
Oh, yeah? Who?
我们需要一架喷气飞机
We're gonna need a jet.
我说我们需要的是一架喷气式飞机
I said we needed a jet.
你知道你少给了我什么吗 时间
Yeah, you know what you didn't give me? Time.
还有钱 我又不是喷气机做的
Or money. I'm not made of jets.
我还以为你是最棒的呢 像个真正的专业人士
I thought you were supposed to be the best. Like a real pro.
哦 对不起 女沙皇
Oh, I beg your pardon, tsarina.
是免费公寓和终生供应的东欧甜点不合您心意吗
Was the free flat and lifetime supply of kissel not to your liking?
- 哈 - 你别被她惹急了
- Ha! - Don't let her wind you up.
不 我反对有人质疑我的专业性
No, I take exception to impugning my professionalism.
行吧 但你确实给我装了一个六小时后就坏掉的发电机
Well, you did set me up with a generator that crapped out after six hours.
你也开始了是吗 真是好搭档啊
You, too, huh? Tag team.
啊 他好敏感 我明白你为什么把他留在身边了
Aw, he's sensitive. See why you keep him around.
其他的呢
Where's the rest?
瞧
Voila.
哦呜
Ooh.
噢 那个是大概五年前我藏起来的
Oh, I stashed that, like, five years ago.
怎么样
How is it?
很干巴 真的很干
It's dry. It's really dry.
你知道吗 你的账款快花光了
You know, you're getting dangerously close to running out your tab.
物资能记在我账上 但是你让我引起当局的注意了
Supplies I can tally, but you bring me attention from the authorities,
我收的价格涨了
all my prices go up.
那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你的朋友 罗斯国务卿 一直在打探我的事
Your mate, Secretary Ross, has been sniffing around my affairs.
以至于我的联系人都不接我的电话
to the point at which I've got contacts declining my calls.
我是个私人承包商
I'm a private contractor.
你确实很敏感
You are sensitive.
你是真的很烦人
You're a very annoying individual.
- 我会补偿你的 - 嗯哼
- I'll make it up to you. - Mmm-hmm.
你每次都这么说
That's what you say every time.
所以 我拿到了核武器密码
So, I have the nuclear code.
但是他就在那
But there he is.
- 美国队长 - 美国
- Captain America! - America.
属于红色守卫者的时刻终于来临了
Finally, the Red Guardian's time has come!
我抓住他的盾牌
I grab hold of his shield.
面对面地 考验力量的时候到了
and face to face, it's a test of strength.
哦…哦不
Oh… Oh, no.
哦…
Oh…
那个家伙还以为他能打败我呢
That guy think he going to beat me.
总之这面盾牌 你们知道的 他总是随身带着
Anyway, this shield, you know, that he carries with him.
就像小宝宝珍贵的毯子一样 懂吧
like a precious baby blanket, you know?
我利用了这一点 我夺走了盾牌
I use it to my advantage. I take it.
把他推出了窗外
and I push him out the window.
然后我成功逃走了 怎么样
And I make my escape. Huh?
你说的是哪一年
What year was this?
我记不太清楚了 大概83 84年
I don't know. Like, '83, '84.
我知道了
I know.
美国队长那个时候还被冻在冰块里呢
Captain America was still frozen in ice then.
你是觉得我在撒谎吗 大熊
Are you calling me a liar, Ursa, huh?
阿列克谢·肖斯塔科夫 收到邮件
Alexei Shostakov1 Mail Call.
噢 不
Oh, no.
啊哦
Uh-oh.
阿列克谢·肖斯塔科夫 收到邮件
Alexei Shostakov1 Mail Call.
哦 瞧瞧这个大熊
Aw, look at the big bear.
要哭了吗 小姑娘
Gonna cry, little girl?
大名鼎鼎的「红色守卫者」
The famed "Red Guardian."
你在回信里叫你的粉丝多放点黄油
When you write back, tell your fans to use more butter.
拿着啊
Take it!
快点
Come on.
红色守卫者上前 喇叭里在喊你
Red Guardian forward! The trumpet is calling.
今天是你的幸运日 阿列克谢
Today is your lucky day, Alexei.
到南边墙上的门那里去
Move to the door on the south wall.
你怎么回事
What's up with you?
你不认字吗
Can't you read?
往左边走
Go left.
别引起太多人注意
Just don't make a scene.
红色守卫者跑了
The Red Guardian is escaping!
你引起所有人的注意了 是吧
You made a scene, didn't you?
现在呢
What now?
我们带你离开这里
We're gettin' you outta here.
上楼
Go to the upper level.
赶紧的 超级士兵
Move your ass, super soldier.
他不可能成功的
He's never going to make it.
靠近一点
Get me closer.
你有更好的主意吗
You got a better idea?
娜塔莎
Natasha.
可真会摆姿势
Such a poser.
认真的吗
Seriously?
呜
Whoo!
对不起
Sorry!
你在干嘛呢 你在逗我吗
What are you doing? Are you kidding me?
退后
Back up!
我们俩干得都很漂亮
We're both doing a really good job.
不
No.
好了 我受够了
Okay. Enough of this.
哈
Ha!
哇哦…
Whoa…
这样的死法还挺酷的
This would be a cool way to die.
告诉我那是个好兆头
Tell me that's a good sign for us!
快点
Move your ass!
带我们离开这里
Get us outta here!
哈
Huh.
等等
Wait!
好耶
Yes!
我这儿需要点帮助
I need some help up here!
拜拜了 傻逼们
Farewell, douchebags.
刚刚可真够刺激的
Oh, that was exciting.
姑娘们 我太为你们骄傲了
Oh, I'm so proud of you girls.
噢 你们听不到我说话 是吧
Oh, you can't hear me, huh?
好吧
Okay.
啊…
Ah…
哇
Wow.
好吧
Okay.
这么凶干什么
Why the aggression, huh?
你赶上生理期了吗
Is it your time of the month?
我没有生理期 蠢蛋 我没有子宫
I don't get my period, dipshit. I don't have a uterus.
也没有卵巢
Or ovaries.
对 红房强迫你进行子宫切除手术的结果就是这样
Yeah. That's what happens when the Red Room gives you an involuntary hysterectomy.
他们就伸进你的肚子里 然后把你所有的生育器官全掏出来
They kind of just go in and they rip out all of your reproductive organs.
他们差不多就是直接进去 把那些器官全切下来
They just get right in there and they chop them all away.
- 所有东西都掏出来了 你就不能生育了 - 行了行了
- Everything out, so you can't have babies. - Okay, okay. Okay! Okay!
没必要说得那么直观恶心
You don't have to get so clinical and nasty.
哦 我本来还想说说输卵管的事的 但是好吧 算了
Oh, well, I was about to talk about fallopian tubes, but okay. No.
我对你们回来救我感到很感动
It means so much to me that you came back for me.
不 不 你要告诉我们怎么去红房
No. No. You're gonna tell us how to get to the Red Room.
哈
Huh.
哇 看看你 一副公事公办的样子
Whoa, look at you, huh? All business.
相信我 这一点都不好玩
Trust me, this isn't pleasure.
小娜塔莎已经完全被灌输了西方理念了
Little Natasha, all indoctrinated into the Western agenda.
我自愿选择前往西方成为一名复仇者
I chose to go west to become an Avenger.
因为他们待我如家人
'Cause they treated me like family.
真的吗 家人
Really? Family?
他们现在在哪儿呢
Well, where are they now?
你那些家人现在在哪儿呢
Where is that family now?
告诉我红房在哪里
Tell me where the Red Room is.
我不知道
I have no idea.
好吗
Okay?
拜托 你和德雷科夫亲近得就像是…
Come on. You and Dreykov were like…
- 德雷科夫 - 对
- Dreykov? - Yeah.
德雷科夫将军 是我的朋友 是吗
General Dreykov, my friend, huh?
他给了我荣耀…
Gives me glory…
苏联的第一个 也是绝无仅有的超级士兵
Soviet Union's first and only super soldier.
我本可以比美国队长更家喻户晓
I could have been more famous than Captain America.
然后他派我去执行那个蠢任务 把我埋在俄亥俄州
Then he buries me in Ohio on that stupid mission.
整整三年哪
Three years!
无聊到我都想哭
So tedious, boring me to tears.
无意冒犯 好吗
No offense, huh?
然后他把我扔进监狱里 让我在那里度过余生 为什么
Then puts me in prison for the rest of my life. Why, huh?
为什么 为什么他要把我扔进…你们知道为什么吗
Why? Why would he put me in… You know why?
可能因为是我想说说国家的衰败
'Cause maybe I want to talk about the withering of the state.
或者可能是因为我不喜欢他的发型之类的
Or maybe I don't like his hair or something.
然后随口说了一句什么
and I say something casually about that.
或者可能 你知道的 我想让党
Maybe, you know, I want the Party.
成为一个真正的党 而不是这样讨人厌的组织
to feel actually like a party instead of this sourpuss organization.
但是 不行
But instead, no.
他把我扔在监狱里让我在那里度过余生
He puts me in prison for the rest of my life.
然后他直接逃跑躲起来了
He just runs off and hides, huh?
我甚至不是那个 呃…
I'm not even the one who, uh, you know…
我甚至不是那个杀了他女儿的人
I'm not the one who killed his daughter.
我们可以现在就把他扔出窗外吗
Can we throw him out the window now?
我们应该爬升到更高海拔再说
I think we should wait till we get to a higher altitude.
好
All right.
为什么不问问梅丽娜红房在哪
Why not ask Melina where it is?
等下 梅丽娜妈妈
Wait, Mom Melina?
我们以为她早死了
We thought she was dead.
狐狸可没那么容易被杀死
You cannot kill a fox that swift.
- 够恶心 - 怎么了吗
- Ew. - What?
她是出谋划策的科学家战略家
She was the scientist, the strategist.
我是出体力的
I was the muscle.
她很早就在德雷科夫手下干活了 比我还早
She worked directly for Dreykov far more than I ever did.
等下 你是说梅丽娜现在还为红房干活吗
Wait. Are you telling me that Melina is working for the Red Room present day?
她在圣彼得堡外的郊区工作
She works remotely outside St. Petersburg.
嗯…
Uh…
我觉得剩余的油不够我们去圣彼得堡了
I don't think we have enough fuel for St. Petersburg.
问题不大 我们能过去的
No, we're good. We'll make it.
行吧
Okay.
你应该开复仇者联盟的超级战机过来的
You should've brought the Avengers' superjet.
我发誓要是再听到他多说一个词
I swear, if I hear one more word from him,
- 我就踹他脸上 - 他最讨人嫌了
- I will kick him in the face. - He's the worst.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
娜塔莎 娜塔莎
Natasha. Natasha.
过来 我想问你点事
Come here, I want to ask you something.
- 来嘛 很重要的 - 干嘛
- Come, it's important. - What?
他有跟你说过我吗
Did he talk to you about me?
什么
What?
他有没有跟你提到我 你懂的 互相交流一下战斗的故事
Did he talk to you about me? You know, trading war stories?
- 谁啊 你在说谁 - 美国队长
- Who? What are you talking about? - Captain America.
在这场地缘政治冲突中 他是我最大的敌人
My great adversary in this theater of geopolitical conflict.
我也不算是败得彻头彻尾
Not so much a nemesis.
我们更像是同时代的 你懂吗 势均力敌
More like a contemporary, you know? Coequal.
我一直觉得我们肯定非常地互相尊重…
I always thought there was a great deal of mutual respect…
行了 你已经二十年没见过我俩了
Wait. You haven't seen either one of us in 20 years.
然后你就问我关于你的事吗
and you're gonna ask me about you?
这么剑拔弩张的干什么
What is with this tension?
是我做错了什么吗
Did I do something wrong?
你说这话是认真的吗
Is that a serious question?
我一直爱着你们
I only ever loved you girls.
我尽我所能 确保你们会成功地
I did my best to make sure you would succeed.
激发所有的潜力
to achieve your fullest potential,
- 然后一切都很顺利 - 一切都很顺利吗
- and everything worked out. - Everything worked out?
是的 对你们来说 是的
Yes. For you, yes.
我们在俄亥俄州完成了任务
We accomplished our mission in Ohio.
叶莲娜 你变成了最牛的少年杀手 闻名世界
Yelena, you went on to become the greatest child assassin the world has ever known.
没人像你这样高效 冷酷
No one can match your efficiency, your ruthlessness.
至于你 娜塔莎
And Natasha,
你不仅仅是颠覆政权的
not just a spy, not just toppling regimes,
或是从内部瓦解帝国的间谍
destroying empires from within,
你还是一名复仇者
but an Avenger.
你们俩都杀人
You both have killed.
无数
so many people.
你们身上一定背负着鲜红的血债
Your ledgers must be dripping, just gushing red.
我真为你们骄傲的不得了
I couldn't be more proud of you.
行了 你可以…不
Okay. You can… No.
赶快放开我
Let go of me now.
你太臭了
You smell really bad.
所以我们到了吗
So, are we there yet?
到了你就知道了
You'll know when we're there.
向右一点
Slight right.
直走
Straight on.
向右
Right.
再向右一点
Slight right.
噢 太棒了我的小宝贝
Oh, very good, my darling.
非常好
Yes, very good.
很棒 很棒 我的小宝贝
Yes, very good, my darling.
回安全的家里去吧 快点去吧
Back home where it's safe. Come on. Go on.
亲爱的
Honey,
我们回家了
we're home.
来吧 姑娘们
Come on, girls.
欢迎光临寒舍
Welcome to my humble abode.
别客气
Make yourself at home.
我们来喝一杯吧
Let's have a drink.
嘿 你别耍花招
Hey, no funny business.
我在把我的武器放起来呢
I am putting away my weapon.
这儿有什么陷阱吗 有什么需要我们了解的吗
Are there any booby traps around here? Anything we need to know about?
我把我的姑娘们养大 可没教你们跑陷阱里去
I didn't raise my girls to fall in traps.
你压根就没养过我们
You didn't raise us at all.
噢 也许吧
Oh, maybe so.
但要是你们心软了 可不是我的锅
But if you got soft, it wasn't on my watch.
我们喝吧
Let's drink.
哎
Okay.
依旧合身
Still fits.
救命啊
Oh, my God.
我从没洗过那衣服
I never washed it once.
来一起喝酒吧
Come and drink.
站起来吧 解放了的工人们
Rise, you workers of salvation.
一家人
Family.
终于重聚了
back together again.
- 嗯 - 基于我们的
- Mmm. - Seeing as our.
家庭关系就是一个只维持了三年的骗局
family construct was just a calculated ruse that only lasted three years,
所以我觉得用「家人」二字不太合适了 对吧
I don't think that we can use this term anymore, can we?
没错 听着接下来情况是这样…
Agreed. So, here's what's gonna happen…
行吧 那就叫重聚咯
Okay. A reunion then, huh?
嗯…
And, uh…
我现在有话不吐不快
I want to say something right off the bat.
你一点都没变 是吧
You haven't aged a day, huh?
你还是那么美丽柔顺
You're just as beautiful.
就和当初他们假造我俩婚姻的时候一模一样
and as supple as the day they staged our marriage.
你胖了
You got fat.
但还是那么厉害
But still good.
我刚从监狱出来 所以我 呃…
I just got out of prison. I, uh…
- 我精力很充沛哦 - 噢
- I have a lot of energy. - Oh!
求求了 千万别
Please don't do that.
所以 情况是这样
So, here's what's gonna happen.
娜塔莎 别驼背
Natasha, don't slouch.
- 我没有驼背 - 有 有 你有
- I'm not slouching. - Yes, yes, you are.
我不驼背
I don't slouch.
你背上都快有隆起了
You're going to get a back hunch.
- 听你妈的话 - 哦天哪 这…
- Listen to your mother. - Oh, my God, this…
挺直 挺直
Up, up.
行吧 够了 你们所有人都闭嘴
All right, enough. All of you.
我什么也没说 这不公平
I didn't say anything. That's not fair.
- 所以 情况是这样… - 我什么也不想吃
- Here's what's gonna happen… - I don't want any food.
吃点东西吧 叶莲娜 好歹给个面子
Eat a little something, Yelena, for God's sake.
你得告诉我们红房的位置
You're gonna tell us the location of the Red Room.
你知道 这就像是你告诉她们
You know, it's like when you told them that.
- 她们可以熬夜等到圣诞老人一样 - 什么
- they could stay up late to catch Santa Claus. - What?
那可真好玩 就说「他会从烟囱爬下来 姑娘们」
That was fun. You know, "He come down the chimney, girls.
「注意啦 他在哪」
"Look out. Where is he?"
你们等着他 然后等饼干都吃没了的时候
You wait for him, and then when the cookies are gone,
你们就能看见他就在那
then you see he's there.
不不 什么 我想让她们追随她们的梦想
No, no. What? I want them to follow their dreams.
- 那没什么好处 - 去摘星星吧 姑娘们
- No good. - Reach for the stars, girls.
寻找德雷科夫可不是个幻想 那是项未完成的工作
Finding Dreykov is not a fantasy. It's unfinished business.
你打败不了一个控制着别人绝对意志的人
You can't defeat a man who commands the very will of others.
你们从来没见过我们之前在美国开启事业的巅峰
You never saw the culmination of what we started in America.
你也没有
Nor did you.
娜塔莎 永远集中注意力 集中 去得到你想要的
Natasha, always focus, focus. Get what you want.
进来
Come in.
那只猪刚刚自己开了门吗
Did that pig just open the door?
是的 它开了
Yes. It did.
好孩子 阿列克谢 好孩子
Good boy, Alexei. Good boy.
你给猪起了我的名字么
You named a pig after me?
你没发现你俩的相似之处吗
You don't see the resemblance?
看 它可以像狗一样坐着
See, he sits just like dog.
太棒了 现在 看着
Amazing. Now, watch.
我感觉这有点诡异
It's a little weird, to me.
停止呼吸
Stop breathing.
我们潜入了俄亥俄州的北方研究所
We infiltrated the North Institute in Ohio.
那曾经是神盾局科学家的前线
It was a front for S.H.I.E.L.D. scientists.
实际上 在那时候应该叫九头蛇的科学家
Actually, it was Hydra scientists at that time.
与冬日战士项目协力
In conjunction with the Winter Soldier project,
他们解剖并且解构了人类大脑
they had dissected and deconstructed the human brain.
创造出了第一个也是唯一一个基底神经节的细胞蓝图
to create the first and only cellular blueprint of the basal ganglia.
那是认知能力的核心
Was the hub for cognition.
自主驱动的运动 阶段性的学习
Voluntary motor movement, procedural learning.
我们没有窃取武器或者科技
We didn't steal weaponry or technology.
我们窃取了解放自由意志的钥匙
We stole the key to unlocking free will.
你到底在干什么
What are you doing?
哦 我正在解释现在这种科学已经发展得非常精确
Oh, I am explaining that the science is now so exact,
你可以命令实验品停止呼吸
the subject can be instructed to stop breathing.
而他们毫无选择只能遵守
and has no choice but to obey.
行了 你已经说得很明白 够了
Okay, you made your point. That's enough.
是的 好吧 别担心 阿列克谢在没有氧气的情况下
Yes, all right. Well, don't worry, Alexei could've survived.
还能再活11秒
11 more seconds without oxygen.
好孩子 现在 你回去吧 回到安全的家里
Good boy. Now, you go back, back home where it's safe.
走吧 回家 回到安全的家里
You go. You go back home, back home where it's safe.
好孩子 阿列克谢
Good boy, Alexei.
当世界被控制的时候 它会以更高的水平运转
The world functions on a higher level when it is controlled.
德雷科夫已经把用化学方法控制了的特工安插在了全球各地
Dreykov has chemically subjugated agents planted around the globe.
那你知道他们在什么人身上试验吗
And do you know who they test it on?
嗯…
Hmm…
不知道 那不属于我的部门负责
No. That's not my department.
啊 得了吧你
Ah, come on, come on.
- 别对她们撒谎 嗯哼 - 我没撒谎
- Don't lie to them. Hmm? - I'm not lying.
你是德雷科夫的设计师 不是吗
You're Dreykov's architect, huh?
那你是什么 如果我是他的设计师
What were you? If I was his architect,
你就是他的合作伙伴
you were his partner.
- 你是他的生意合作伙伴 - 不不不 我当时容易上当
- You were his business partner. - No, no, no. I was patsy!
- 别跟我说这些… - 他向我兜售观念
- Don't give me that… - He sell me ideology.
- 不要再讲政治了 - 一直以来 更大的…
- Stop with the politics. - All the while, bigger…
闭嘴 你就是个蠢货
Shut up! You are an idiot.
而你是个懦夫
And you're a coward.
你是个懦夫
You're a coward.
我们的家庭从来都不是真的 所以也没什么好为之坚持的
And our family was never real, so there's nothing to hold on to.
我们都在向前看
We're moving on.
从来不是家庭 哈
Never family, huh?
在内心里 我只是一个普通的男人
in my heart, I am simple man.
而且我觉得对于一对深深潜伏的俄国特工来说
And I think that for a couple deep undercover Russian agents.
我们作为家长做得还不错 对吧
I think we did pretty great as parents, huh?
对 我们有我们的任务 而且把我们的角色做到了完美
Yes, we had our orders, and we played our roles to perfection.
谁在意 那又不是真的
Who cares? That wasn't real.
- 什么 - 那不是真的
- What? - That wasn't real.
- 谁在意 - 别那么说
- Who cares? - Don't say that.
求你不要那样说 那是真的
Please don't say that. It was real.
对我来说是真的 你是我的母亲
It was real to me. You are my mother.
你曾是我真正的母亲
You were my real mother.
那是我和一个人曾经拥有的最亲密的关系
The closest thing I ever had to one.
我人生中最好的部分是假的
The best part of my life was fake.
而且你们都没告诉过我
And none of you told me.
还有那些特工
And those agents.
你们可以在全球范围内通过化学方法控制他们
you chemically subjugated around the globe?
我就是被控制的那个人
That was me.
嗯
Mmm.
还有你 你逃出去了
And you, you got out.
德雷科夫总是确保再也没有一个人能逃得出去
Dreykov made sure no one could escape.
你打算说什么吗
Are you gonna say anything?
没有
No.
不要碰我
Don't touch me.
叶莲娜
Yelena.
不
No.
- 我从来都不知道 - 没关系的 没关系
- I had no idea. - It's okay, it's okay.
我去和她聊聊
I'll go talk to her.
我进这里是因为我不想说话
I came in here because I didn't want to talk.
好的
Okay.
我们 呃…我们就坐着
We, uh… We just sit.
我们就坐着
We just sit.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
我自己来做这件事
To do this myself.
别这样 你会死的
Don't. You won't survive.
我真希望我能相信你是在乎我的
I wish I could believe that you cared.
但你甚至都不是第一个遗弃我的母亲
But you're not even the first mother that abandoned me.
不 你不是被遗弃的
No, you weren't abandoned.
你是被一个程序选中了
You were selected by a program that.
一个评估婴儿基因潜能的程序
assessed the genetic potential in infants.
我是被带走的吗
I was taken?
我相信这是达成了协议的 你的家庭也都得到了回报
I believe a bargain was struck, your family paid off.
但你的母亲 她一直在找你
But your mother, she never stopped looking for you.
她和你在那方面很像 她真的
She was like you in that way. She was.
不屈不挠
relentless.
她怎么了
What happened to her?
德雷科夫杀了她
Dreykov had her killed.
她的存在会让红房暴露
Her existence threatened to uncover the Red Room.
通常来说 一个平民好奇的行为不会导致她被处决
Normally, the actions of one curious civilian wouldn't warrant an execution,
但正如我所说 她锲而不舍
but, as I said, she was relentless.
我一生中每一天都在想她
I thought about her every day of my life.
不管我自己内心是否承认 我确实每天都在想她
Whether or not I admitted it to myself, I did.
我一直觉得最好不要回顾过去
I've always found it best not to look into the past.
那你为什么保留着这个
Then why did you save this?
我还记得这一天
I remember this day.
我们在一天内 拍摄了圣诞节 感恩节 复活节还有暑假照片
We shot Christmas, Thanksgiving, Easter and summer vacation all in one day.
- 用不同的背景 - 嗯
- Different backdrops. - Mmm.
我知道树下所有的礼盒都是空的 但是…
I knew all the presents under the tree were just empty boxes, but…
我不在乎 我想打开每个盒子…
I didn't care. I wanted to open every single one…
所以哪怕只有一秒 我都觉得是真的
so just for a second it would feel real.
都停下吧
Let's stop this.
你为什么这么做
Why you doing this?
为什么一只出生在笼子里的老鼠会在那个小轮子上跑
Why does a mouse born in a cage run on that little wheel?
你知道吗 在你甚至还没出生的时候
Do you know I was cycled through the Red Room.
红房的这套流程我已经经历了四回
four times before you were even born?
我只知道那些墙
Those walls are all I know.
我从来都没有选择
I was never given a choice.
但你不是老鼠 梅丽娜
But you're not a mouse, Melina.
你只是生在了一个笼子中 但这不是你的错
You were just born in a cage, but that's not your fault.
告诉我 你是怎么保持你的本心的
Tell me, how did you keep your heart?
痛苦只会让我们变得更强
Pain only makes us stronger.
这不是你告诉我们的吗
Didn't you tell us that?
我靠着你教我的东西活了下来
What you taught me kept me alive.
对不起 我已经通知了红房 他们随时都可能到
I'm sorry, I already alerted the Red Room. They'll be here any minute.
所以 我和我父亲在冰面上钓鱼
So, there I am ice fishing with my father.
这天这个小冰棚里真的很冷
It's very cold day in this little ice shed.
即使对俄罗斯来说也冷
Cold even for Russia, you know?
我父亲会对我说
"Keep the vodka by the fire, "
- 「把伏加特放在炉火旁」 - 请别说了
- my father would say to me. - Please stop talking.
- 等等 等等 拜托了 - 请不要再说了 拜托 我不想说话
- Please wait. Please wait. Please. - Please, no. Please, I don't want to talk.
拜托
Please.
我跟你讲这个是有原因的 好吗 相信我
There is a reason why I'm telling you this, okay? Trust me.
我伸手去抓鱼
I am reaching for fish.
天呐 我失去平衡了 啊
Oh! I lose balance. Ah!
水花四溅
Splash!
我的手伸进了河里
My hands go in the river.
在这种天气里 很快会被冻伤
In this weather, frostbite sets in quick.
- 我父亲 他在我手上撒尿 - 噢 天呐
- My father, he go toilet on my hands. - Oh, my God.
尿液温度为35摄氏度 可以防止冻伤
Urine is 35 degrees Celsius, staves off the frostbite.
这跟我有什么联系吗
How is this relevant?
你知道的
You know,
父亲们都是这样
fathers.
不 不是的
No. No.
你什么也没做 只是告诉我你感觉多么无聊
You have done nothing but tell me how bored you were.
我只是一个无聊的任务 一个你不想做的任务
I was the chore, the job you didn't want to do.
但对我来说呢
To me?
对我来说 你就是一切
To me, you were everything.
确实 你根本不在乎
Exactly. You don't care.
你不在乎
You don't care.
你唯一在意的是你那愚蠢的光辉岁月
The only thing you care about are your stupid glory days.
就像是漫画里的绯红机甲 但没有人想听
as the Crimson Dynamo, and no one wants to hear about it.
是红色守卫者
It's the Red Guardian.
出去
Get out.
立马出去
Get out!
我已经不记得
I can't remember.
自己有没有哭
If I cried.
当我知晓了他那寡居的新娘
When I read about his widowed bride.
有什么触动了我的心弦
Something touched me deep inside.
在音乐
The day.
死亡的
The music.
那天
Died.
他们高声唱着
And they were singing.
- 再见吧 - 再见吧
- Bye - Bye.
- 美国派小姐 - 美国派
- Miss American Pie - American Pie.
开着雪佛兰上河堤
Drove my Chevy to the levee.
- 而河堤已干涸 - 已干涸
- But the levee was dry - Was dry.
老朋友们
Them good old boys.
喝着威士忌
Drinking whiskey.
高声唱着
Singing.
「今日就是死期」
"This will be the day that I die"
「今日就是…」
"This'll be the day…"
趴下
Get down.
就这…
They think…
抱歉
I'm sorry.
别让他再等了
Let's not keep him waiting.
请求降落许可
Request clearance for landing.
收到 你可以在5号机坪降落
Copy that. You are cleared to land on bay 5.
梅丽娜
Melina?
我们将在一分钟内降落
We're touching down in one minute.
那我们为什么还在上升
Then why are we still going up?
现在你就知道德雷科夫如何隐匿这么多年了
Now you'll know how Dreykov stayed above the radar all these years.
（红房）
天呐
My God.
你来了
Look at you.
所以 呃
So, uh,
和家人们的重聚如何
how was the family reunion?
噢 十分糟糕
Oh, it was awful.
他们真粘人 特别情绪化 渴望精神支撑
They were clingy, and too emotional, and needy.
- 就跟以前一样 对吗 - 没错
- Just like old times, huh? - Hmm.
叶莲娜·贝洛娃
Yelena Belova.
她到底怎么回事
What's the deal with her?
只有她一个人受影响 对吗
She was the only one affected, right?
据我所知 没错
As far as I know, yes.
这些气体解药 是我的眼中钉肉中刺
These gasses and antidotes, it's a pain in my ass.
是一个棘手的问题 你得解决一下
It's a problem. You need to sort it.
嗯 我有九只小猪
Hmm. I have nine pigs.
- 我不在的时候需要人照顾呢 - 别管你的那些猪了
- that will require attending to in my absence. - Don't give a shit about your pigs.
解剖她的大脑…
Cut her brain out…
嗯 找到她的弱点
Hmm? Identify the weakness.
就这样死掉一点都不酷
This is a much less cool way to die.
阿列克谢
Alexei.
罗曼诺夫怎么办
What about Romanoff?
她是个叛徒
She's a traitor.
她背叛了她的人民以及她的血缘至亲
She turned her back on her people. On her blood.
她现在一无所有
She had nothing.
我曾给过她一个家 给过她爱
I gave her home. I gave her love.
把你的那套东西也注射到她身上
Put that thing in her you do.
那些你研制出的化学药剂
You know, uh, chemicals.
将她也变为你的一只小猪
Turn her into one of your pigs.
你能想象我控制一名复仇者之后会有多大能耐吗
Can you imagine what I could do with an Avenger under my control?
难道你不想先和她谈谈吗
Wouldn't you like to speak to her first?
当你看向由你抚养长大的孩子的眼睛时
When you look into the eyes of a child you have raised,
流露出的情感是不会被掩盖的
no mask in the world can hide that.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
先别急
Now, now.
别着急弄坏了我的新玩具
Don't go breaking my new toy.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
我救不出咱俩
I can't save us.
我得让你知道我很抱歉
I need you to know that I'm sorry.
我把我的生命献给一项事业
I pledged my life to a cause.
你知道 我曾以为我十分勇敢
You know, I thought I was being very brave.
也许是最勇敢的那位 但其实并不是
Possibly the bravest. But I wasn't being brave.
我十分懦弱
I was coward.
在古巴
In Cuba,
当他们将你们从我身边带走时…
when they came and took you away from me…
没有什么事业是值得的
No cause is worth that.
你只有为了某件值得事情
You should only sacrifice yourself.
才能牺牲自己…
for something…
你咋开门的
How did you do that?
因为这些牢房是我设计的
I designed these cells myself.
什么玩意
What?
怎么回事
我的肺腑之言都说给你听了吗
I bared my soul to you and it was just you the whole time?
恐怕没错 但是稍等 我正在和叶莲娜通讯
Yes, I'm afraid so. But wait, shh, I'm on comms with Yelena.
叶莲娜 妈妈在和你说话
Yelena, it's me. It's Mama.
在你的腰带里藏着一把两英尺的匕首
You have a two-inch blade concealed in your beltline.
什么
What?
你们要对我做什么
What are you going to do to me?
右边大腿外侧
Outside right hip.
让她保持清醒准备开颅
Keep her awake for the cranial incisions.
你就不能早点告诉我吗
You couldn't have told me sooner?
别闹小脾气
Don't throw a fit.
- 之前没有机会 - 好了女孩们
- There wasn't time. - Okay, girls,
我听不见你们说话
I'm having trouble hearing you,
但是 娜塔莎 我需要你明白一些事情
but, Natasha, there's something I need you to know.
我需要你知道我非常抱歉 我不会再找借口了 好吗
I need you to know that I'm sorry. No more excuses, okay?
我把我的生命献给一项事业 我曾认为我十分勇敢
I gave my life for a cause. I thought I was being brave.
你没有对讲耳机
You don't have earpiece.
啥玩意
What?
意思是她听不见你讲话
No, she can't hear you.
- 你没有带对讲耳机 - 我为啥没有
- You don't have earpiece. - Why not?
因为这不是计划中的一部分
Because it wasn't part of the plan.
噢 是吗 那计划是怎样的
Oh, yeah? Well, what was the plan?
所以 一旦我们进入内部
So, once we're inside,
我就会启动身上的追踪器 罗斯会追查到此地
I'll activate my tracker and Ross will come running.
你还记得自己是一名全球通缉犯呢
You are aware that you are still a global fugitive, yes?
你了解这里的设备 一定有办法能让它降落
You know the facility. There must be some way to land it.
引诱他们在第零层囚禁我们
Instruct them to confine us on level zero.
一旦我逃出 我就能启动降落程序
Once I'm out, I can activate the landing protocol,
我们能在一小时内降落到地面
we can descend within the hour.
啊哦 问题来了
Ah, problem.
我只有一套对讲耳机设备
I only have one earpiece set.
留给叶莲娜吧
I'll give it to Yelena.
他把解药放在哪里了
Where did he take the vials?
也许在冷藏室里
Probably down to cold storage.
德雷科夫仍控制着那些姑娘
Dreykov still has the widows under his control,
所以你得让她们暴露在解药环境下
so you have to expose them to this antidote.
当然 小事一桩
Yeah. Sure. Easy.
这就是你的计划吗
Is this your plan?
我的计划是杀了你
My plan is to kill you.
我还活着
I'm alive.
所以 我们现在要干什么
So, what do we do now?
我的母亲叫什么名字
What was my mother's name?
啊…
Ah…
我们埋葬她的地方
Where we buried her,
有一棵树…
there was a tree…
嗯…
Um…
一簇粉红的花
A pink blossom.
很漂亮
Beautiful.
还有一块墓碑
And there was a tombstone.
上面刻着她的名字
with her name engraved on it.
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
啊
Ah.
「无名氏」
"Unknown."
你没有任何感觉吗
You don't feel anything?
我杀死你的女儿的时候 你有什么感觉吗
You feel anything when I killed your daughter?
这是你的旧日阴影吗
Is this your haunted past?
真的吗
Really?
谢谢你 娜塔莎
Thank you, Natasha.
你给了我最强大的武器
You gave me my greatest weapon.
打个招呼吧
Say hello.
你们的炸弹爆炸的时候
When your bomb exploded,
差点炸死了我的安东尼娅
it nearly killed my Antonia.
我不得不在她的后颈里装一块芯片
I had to put a chip in the back of her neck.
在她的后颈里
In the back of her neck.
看看她
Look at her.
你觉得她让你难以直视吗
You find it difficult to look at her?
我就这么觉得
I do.
她…她观察着一切
She… She watches everything.
然后复制出来
and she can do it.
她是一个完美的模仿者
She's a perfect mimic.
她的战斗方式与你所有的朋友一样
And she fights just like all of your friends.
她能听到我说话吗
Can she hear me?
怎么
What?
你想让她好受些
You want to make her feel better?
你想跟她说对不起么
You want to tell her you're sorry?
那你在把她的脸炸掉之前就该想到这些
Well, you should have thought of that before you blew her face off.
但是废话说够了
But enough of all this bullshit.
干活去
Go to work.
我的地库里有几只老鼠 去
I have rats in the basement. Go.
去吧
Go.
你犯了个错误
Well, that was a mistake.
是吗
Was it?
你刚刚把唯一能阻止我杀你的东西送走了
You just sent away the one thing that would stop me from killing you.
那就试试吧
Try, then.
动手
Do it.
子弹没上膛吗
Is the safety on?
上了
No.
试试用刀
Try your knife.
啊…
Ah…
你遇上麻烦了
You're in trouble.
你是怎么控制我的
How are you controlling me?
我没有控制你 娜塔莎
I'm not controlling you, Natasha.
好吧 现在还没有
Well, not yet.
但是我有一把信息素锁
But there is a pheromonal lock.
只要嗅到我的信息素 你就无法对我作出暴力举动
Smelling my pheromones prevents you from committing violence against me.
我对梅丽娜很失望
I'm very upset with Melina.
真可惜我不得不杀了她
It's a shame I have to kill her.
拜托啦 如果我们只是要
Come on, now. If we're just going to.
按下按钮和黑掉电脑…
press buttons and hack computers…
- 是的 - 我是说 我不知道
- Yes. - I mean, I don't know.
那就没有我能做的事了
There's nothing for me to do.
我想…我想砸点东西
I want to… I want to break something.
哦 是吗
Oh, you do?
哦 你有东西砸了
Oh, there is something you can break.
梅丽娜 如果这是我们最后一次…
Melina, if this is the last time that we…
啊 该死的
Ah, damn it.
刚才那下真恶心
That was disgusting.
行吧
Okay.
所以 这就是你们的惊天计划 嗯
So, this was the big plan, huh?
梅丽娜要把红房迫降 把我交给政府机关
Melina was going to land the Red Room and hand me over to the authorities.
哦 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
所以 现在怎么样 你要把我塞进你那可悲的小小木偶戏里吗
So, what now, you're gonna fold me into your pathetic little puppeteer act?
可悲的 是吗
Pathetic, huh?
是啊 你怎么称呼它
Yeah, what would you call it?
- 我把它称作… - 你最后一次
- I would call it… - When was the last time that you.
不是强迫别人跟你对话是什么时候
had a conversation with somebody that wasn't forced to talk to you?
你逃到错误的战争中去了
You ran away to fight in the wrong war.
真正的战争是在这里打响的 在阴影之中
The real war was fought here, in the shadows.
你不是在阴影中战斗
You didn't fight in the shadows.
你是躲在黑暗里
You hid in the dark.
真正的力量来自无法察觉的影响
Real power comes from undetectable influence.
如果根本就没人察觉 那为什么还要做呢
If no one's noticed, then why even do it?
你一无是处
You're nothing.
- 唔 - 你一无所有
- Hmm. - You have nothing.
这颗星球上有50个人…
There are 50 people on this planet…
哦 快停下吧
Oh, stop it.
别跟我说停下
Don't tell me to stop!
如果我不叫你停下 你怎么知道什么时候该闭嘴
If I don't tell you when to stop, then how will you know when to shut up?
得了吧
Come on.
以为我受不了拳头吗
Think I can't take a punch?
哦
Oh.
- 天啊 你真软弱 - 软弱
- God damn it, you're weak. - Weak?
对着毫无还手之力的小女孩耍威风更容易 是吧
I bet it's easier to be tough in front of defenseless little girls, huh?
够了
That's enough.
如果你明白我所建立的一切有多庞大
You wouldn't be so glib if you had any notion.
你就不会嘴硬了
of the scope of what I've built.
我拥有整个世界 是我
I own this world. Me.
你看起来是拼命想让我佩服你
You seem desperate to impress me.
我才不需要这么做
I don't need to impress you.
我不需要任何人的佩服
I don't need to impress anyone.
世界上的那些领导 那些伟人
These world leaders, these great men,
他们都得听命于我和我的姑娘们
they answer to me and my widows.
看看她们
Look at them.
这些女孩命如草芥
These girls were trash.
她们被扔到街头
They are thrown out into the street.
我把她们捡回来
I recycle the trash.
赋予她们目标
And I give them purpose.
赋予她们人生
I give them a life.
梅丽娜 我找到解药了
Melina, I found the location of the vials.
我遇到点麻烦
I've had a slight setback.
你得找到那些姑娘们
You'll need to get to the widows.
这就是我的「寡妇」网络
It's my network of widows.
它帮助我掌控权力
that help me control the scales of power.
一道命令下去 石油和股票市场就会崩溃
One command, the oil and stock markets crumble.
一道命令下去 四分之一个地球就会面临饥荒
One command, and a quarter of the planet will starve.
我的姑娘们可以引发战争 也可以结束战争
My widows can start and end wars.
可以缔造统治者 也可以消灭统治者
They can make and break kings.
你就在这里控制着她们所有人吗
You control all of that from here?
而有了你
And with you,
一个受我控制的复仇者
an Avenger under my control,
我就终于可以从阴影中走出去
I can finally come out of the shadows.
利用这个世界上唯一过剩的自然资源
using the only natural resource that the world has too much of.
那就是女孩
Girls.
都是通过那个小小的控制台吗
All from that little console?
是的
Yeah.
噢 你觉得这很好笑吗
Oh, you find this amusing?
你笑什么
Why are you smiling?
别在意 但是 呃…
Don't take it personal, but, uh…
谢谢你的配合
Thank you for your cooperation.
即使你知道了数据库的位置 让他把钥匙展示给你
Even if you locate the database and get him to show you the key,
你也没法从他那里拿走它
you won't be able to take it from him.
多年以来 德雷科夫在所有姑娘身上植入了一种信息素锁
For years, Dreykov has implemented a pheromonal lock.
包括我
in all widows, even me.
所以 只要我们能闻到他的信息素 就没法伤害他
So, as long as we can smell him, then we won't be able to hurt him.
那么 我可以屏住呼吸
Well, I'll just hold my breath.
这还不够
Not enough.
这是基础科学知识
This is basic science.
娜塔莎 要想阻断嗅中枢的受体
Natasha, to block receptors in olfactory center,
你得切断神经
you have to sever the nerve.
我能搞定
I can handle that.
你还不够强大 所以…
You weren't quite strong enough, so…
我得自己来了结这一切
I'll have to finish it myself.
你想干什么
What are you going to do?
切断神经
Sever the nerve.
她有枪
She's got a gun!
梅丽娜
Melina!
梅丽娜 停下
Melina, stop there!
扔掉武器
Drop to the ground!
跟我想的一样
Precisely what I was thinking.
叶莲娜 计划有变
Yelena, slight change of plan.
我刚刚破坏了一个引擎 我们得紧急迫降了
I completely demolished one of the engines and we are going into a controlled crash.
棒极了
Fantastic.
我正在赶往女孩们那边
I'm heading to the widows now.
不
No.
我们得走了
We have to go.
你现在话没那么多了哈
Not so talkative now, are you?
你夺走了我的童年
You took my childhood.
让我别无选择 试图摧毁我
You took my choices and tried to break me.
但你再也无法对其他人这么做了
But you're never gonna do that to anybody ever again.
（正在退出）
任何人都不许离开这个房间 直到她死掉
Nobody leaves this room until she's dead.
好好折磨她
Make her suffer.
我不想伤害你们
I don't wanna hurt you.
你们也并不想伤害我
You don't wanna hurt me.
嘿
Hey.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
看起来很疼
That looks like it hurts.
我数三下然后把它取出来 准备好了吗
Okay. I take out on three, ready?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们现在做什么
What do we do now?
远离这里 越远越好
Get as far away from here as possible.
你们现在可以做出属于自己的选择了
You get to make your own choices now.
我们得离开这里
We gotta get outta here.
- 我们得找到德雷科夫 你来吗 - 我这就跟上来
- We need to find Dreykov. Are you coming? - I'm right behind you.
等等 等等 我得回去
Wait, wait! I have to go back!
（正在登陆）
（启动数据传输）
（数据传输完成）
好了
Yes!
你看到姑娘们了吗
Do you see the girls?
没有
No!
我们得回去
We need to go back.
我们失控了
We've lost control.
安东尼娅
Antonia.
别
No!
我会打开门
I'm gonna open the door.
然后你跟着我走
You're gonna come after me.
没事的 没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
我知道你的真我还在
I know you're still in there.
我不会离开你的 好吗
And I'm not gonna leave you. Okay.
叶莲娜
Yelena!
她在机翼上
She's on the wing!
快去 你们还在等什么
Move! What are you waiting for?
别这样做
Don't do it!
挺有意思的
This was fun!
不
No!
好的
Okay.
那就来吧
Let's go.
够了
Enough.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他死了吗
Is he gone?
他死了
He's gone.
叶莲娜
Yelena!
Yelena?
我们都倒过来了
We're both upside down.
原谅我 小妹妹
Forgive me little sister.
我应该回来找你的
I should've come back for you.
- 你不用说这些的 没关系的 - 嘿 嘿
- You don't have to say that. It's okay. - Hey. Hey.
你们对我来说也是真的
It was real to me, too.
谢谢你
Thank you.
大家都还好吗
Everybody good?
很显然我受伤了
I am clearly injured.
你有话要说吗
You got something to say?
我只会把事情搞砸
I'd just mess it up.
骑兵来了
Here comes the cavalry.
我们正在接近目标 长官
We're closing in on the target, sir.
所以 我们的计划是什么
So, what's our plan?
你们走吧
You guys go.
我留下来
I'll stay.
这太疯狂了 我们战斗 我们和你并肩作战
That's insanity. We fight. We fight with you.
- 我会拖住他们的 - 娜塔莎
- I'll hold them off. - Natasha,
- 我们一起战斗 - 我们不能分开的 你太固执了
- we fight. - We can't split up. You're so pigheaded.
你们快走吧
You guys, go.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
而且 如果我们四个都能成功的话
Besides, if it can work out with the four of us,
复仇者联盟或许还仍有希望
you know, there may be some hope for the Avengers.
一点点希望
Little bit.
好吧 如果你执意要走 我想你应该带上这个
Okay, well, if you're leaving, then I guess you should take this.
我知道你有多喜欢它
I know how much you like it.
行吧
Shucks.
它确实有很多口袋
It does have a lot of pockets.
很方便的口袋 是吧
Very handy pockets, yeah.
他已经把姑娘们植入到了全球各地
He had widows implanted all over the world.
梅丽娜需要复制配方
Melina will need to copy the formula,
但应该由你来告诉她们一切都结束了
but you should be the one to tell 'em it's over.
你们回来找我们了
You came back for us.
我们不会丢下你们的
We wouldn't leave you behind.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 你要照顾好自己 知道吗
Hey. You take care of yourself, okay?
别担心 我记住了
Don't worry. I got this.
我知道
I know.
不用担心 我们会带上她的
Don't worry. We're bringing her with us.
走吧 跟我们来
Come. Come with us.
（2周后）
你从来不睡觉的吗
You ever not sleep?
因为你 我在三天之内到了六个时区
I've been in six different time zones in three days because of you.
哦 真的吗
Oh, really?
当然
Yeah.
怎么 你是把一堆零件拼起来了吗
What, are you scrapping together some parts?
你这次给我带了什么 一个倒立的除草机吗
What'd you get me this time, like, an upside-down lawnmower?
你现在知道我花一点时间和金钱就能给你什么了吗
You see what I can get you with a bit of time and money?
继续 说吧 我想从你嘴里听到
Go on, say it. I wanna hear it.
我真的很高兴听你讲
It would really be good for me to hear it. Really.
我很感动
I'm impressed.
好吧 还有呢
Well, yeah.
你永远是我的一个好朋友
You've always been a really good friend to me.
这真是每一个男人都希望听到的呢
That's what every man wants to hear.
你打算去哪
Where you gonna go?
很有趣 我一辈子都坚信我没有家
It's funny. My whole life, I didn't think I had any family.
结果发现我有了两个家 所以…
Turns out I got two, so…
其中有一个现在遇到了一些麻烦
One of them's a bit of a mess right now.
我得先帮助其中的一些人越狱
I'm gonna go break a few of them out of prison.
看看我能不能解决这个问题吧
see if I can't help patch things up.
来吧 范尼
Come on, Fanny.
（女儿 姐姐 复仇者）
哇哦 真是不好意思
Wow. Sorry.
我对中西部过敏
I'm allergic to the Midwest.
这个女人所做的一切
What this woman did,
老实说 我甚至无法想象
honestly, I can't even imagine.
你不应该在我度假的时候打扰我的 瓦伦蒂娜
You're not supposed to be bothering me on my holiday time, Valentina.
哦 打扰你 不不不
Oh, bothering you? Oh, no, no.
- 我只是来表达一下我的敬意 - 嗯…
- I'm just here paying my respects. - Hmm…
你知道吗 你来这里给我一种孤注一掷的感觉
You know, coming here makes you look desperate.
好吧
Okay.
- 我想要加薪 - 哦 是的 你和我都是
- I want a raise. - Oh, yeah. You and me both.
相信我 你会得到的
Believe me, you're gonna earn it.
我这有你的下一个目标
I've got your next target.
我觉得应该亲手交给你
Thought I'd hand-deliver it.
也许你想亲手杀掉害死你姐姐的人
Maybe you'd like a shot at the man responsible for your sister's death.
他看起来还挺俊 你不觉得吗
Kind of a cutie, don't you think?